Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
We have an advanced lesson for you today.
今天我们为大家准备了一节高级课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
Katrina And my name is Katrin and I'm very excited
Katrina 我是Katrin，我对这节课非常兴奋，
about this lesson, Marco.
Marco。
Marco It's very interesting.
Marco 这节课非常有趣。
It's about a very controversial topic and a very popular person in history, Charles
它涉及一个非常有争议的话题，以及历史上一个非常著名的人物——
Darwin.
查尔斯·达尔文。
Katrina That's right.
Katrina 没错。
So he's most famous perhaps for his book, The Origin
他最著名的可能是他的书《物种起源》，
of the Species and we're going to be talking a lot about science today.
我们今天会大量讨论科学。
So put your thinking caps on.
所以请开动脑筋。
Marco Alright, so without further ado, why don't
Marco 好的，话不多说，我们
we listen to this dialogue for the first time.
先来听一遍这段对话。
Man, it's been forever.
天啊，好久不见了。
What have you been up to lately?
你最近在忙什么？
Charles I've been busy preparing for my exams, not
Charles 我一直在忙着准备考试，更不用说
to mention all the term papers I've had to write.
还得写那么多学期论文。
Katrina Same here.
Katrina 我也是。
I'm up to my neck in work, but at least we've got summer holidays after finals.
我忙得不可开交，但至少期末考试后就是暑假了。
Where are you headed now?
你现在要去哪儿？
Charles I'm going to my anthro class.
Charles 我要去上人类学课。
We've been focusing on Darwin all term since it's the 200th anniversary of his birth
我们整个学期都在讲达尔文，因为今年是他诞辰200周年
or whatever.
之类的。
I'm sick and tired of Darwin, Darwin, Darwin!
我真是受够了达尔文，达尔文，达尔文！
Katrina What?
Katrina 什么？
Why?
为什么？
How can you not like Darwin?
你怎么会不喜欢达尔文？
His work turned thousands of years of ideas about creation on their head.
他的工作颠覆了数千年来关于创造的观点。
His theory of evolution revolutionized the fields of biology and anthropology.
他的进化论彻底改变了生物学和人类学领域。
Charles I don't like him.
Charles 我就是不喜欢他。
His theory of human evolution and natural selection is full of holes.
他的人类进化和自然选择理论漏洞百出。
It's not as solid as you make it out to be.
它并不像你说的那么可靠。
Katrina Say that again and you'll make enemies with
Katrina 你再说一遍，就会和
half of the academy, not to mention your professors.
学术界一半的人结仇，更别说你的教授了。
Furthermore, the explanation proposed by Darwin about the origin of the species and the process
此外，达尔文提出的关于物种起源和
of natural selection constitutes a grand step towards a coherent understanding of the world
自然选择过程的解释，是朝着连贯理解世界
and its very beginnings.
及其起源迈出的重要一步。
Charles I'm not minimizing his huge contributions
Charles 我并不是在贬低他对科学的
to science.
巨大贡献。
It's just that his theory reminds me of the conundrum of the chicken and the egg.
只是他的理论让我想起了鸡和蛋的难题。
Katrina What are you talking about?
Katrina 你在说什么？
Charles Which came first?
Charles 先有哪个？
The chicken or the egg?
鸡还是蛋？
This is a classic logical problem, and I think it applies to Darwin's theory.
这是一个经典的逻辑问题，我认为它适用于达尔文的理论。
How did the very first living organism come to be?
第一个生物体是如何产生的？
Katrina Interesting.
Katrina 有意思。
I think that question is better suited for my philosophy class.
我觉得这个问题更适合在我的哲学课上讨论。
In the meantime, how about we settle this with a duel?
与此同时，我们不如用决斗来解决这个问题？
Alright, interesting, they have very different views on Charles Darwin, right?
好的，有意思，他们对查尔斯·达尔文的看法很不同，对吧？
Katrina They do, and they're both pretty nerdy people.
Katrina 是的，而且他们俩都是挺书呆子气的人。
This is a very nerdy university conversation that's happening between classes.
这是一场课间发生的非常书呆子气的大学对话。
Charles Yeah, I think maybe they're like PhD candidates
Charles 是啊，我觉得他们可能是博士生
or something.
之类的。
Katrina Perhaps.
Katrina 也许吧。
Alright, so before we get to talking about some of
好的，在我们开始讨论
the ideas in today's dialogue, let's talk about some of the words and phrases that we
今天对话中的一些观点之前，我们先来谈谈听到的一些单词和短语，
hear to understand better what's going on.
以便更好地理解内容。
The first part we're going to talk about in today's Language Takeaway.
今天“语言要点”部分的第一部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Charles Alright, on Language Takeaway today, let's
Charles 好的，今天的“语言要点”，我们
take a look at the first word.
先来看第一个词。
And well, one of the things that many people say is that Darwin revolutionized the fields
嗯，很多人说的一件事是，达尔文彻底改变了
of biology.
生物学领域。
Katrina And so he revolutionized these because he
Katrina 他之所以彻底改变了这些领域，是因为他
pushed them forward.
推动了它们的发展。
He made many changes.
他带来了很多变化。
He forced changes.
他迫使了变化。
So people had to change the way that they thought about these things.
所以人们不得不改变对这些事情的看法。
Charles If you revolutionize something, a topic or an idea, you are creating new knowledge
Charles 如果你彻底改变某件事、某个话题或某个想法，你几乎就是在创造新知识，
almost, right?
对吧？
Katrina Exactly.
Katrina 没错。
You can think of the word revolution, which is a thing.
你可以想想“革命”这个词，它是一个名词。
So you think of the Russian Revolution or the American Revolution.
比如俄国革命或美国革命。
These are times of change.
这些都是变革的时代。
So to revolutionize is to bring about change.
所以“彻底改变”就是带来变革。
Charles Very good.
Charles 很好。
Alright, so moving forward, they were talking about human evolution.
好的，继续往下，他们谈到了人类进化。
Human evolution.
人类进化。
What is that exactly?
那到底是什么？
Katrina Good question.
Katrina 好问题。
So you're not a monkey.
你不是猴子。
I'm not a monkey, but we come from monkeys, right?
我也不是猴子，但我们是从猴子进化来的，对吧？
Charles So we evolved.
Charles 所以我们进化了。
Katrina Right.
Katrina 对。
So the process is called human evolution.
这个过程就叫人类进化。
That means the process by which humans changed forms to become what we are today.
意思是人类改变形态，成为今天这个样子的过程。
Charles Okay, so you evolve.
Charles 好的，所以你进化。
Now is it evolution?
那么是进化吗？
You usually think of something positive, right?
你通常认为它是积极的，对吧？
Something evolves into something better.
某物进化成更好的东西。
Is it always that way?
总是这样吗？
Katrina No, we have another word for the negative,
Katrina 不，我们有另一个词表示消极的，
right?
对吧？
So the positive is to evolve, to become better.
所以积极的是“进化”，变得更好。
To get worse is to devolve.
变差就是“退化”。
Charles Okay.
Charles 好的。
Katrina Yeah, to devolve, to go back and to kind of
Katrina 是的，“退化”，就是倒退，并且
lose things that you had.
失去你曾经拥有的东西。
Charles Okay, interesting.
Charles 好的，有意思。
And then they were also talking about Darwin's theory of natural selection.
然后他们还谈到了达尔文的自然选择理论。
Natural selection.
自然选择。
Katrina Okay, this is maybe one of the things that
Katrina 好的，这可能是达尔文
Darwin was most famous for, and that's why we've included it in this language takeaway
最著名的一点，所以我们把它放在这个语言要点里，
because it's a key phrase.
因为它是一个关键短语。
It's something you hear people talk about a lot.
这是你经常听到人们谈论的东西。
Okay, so natural selection is a process again, and it's the process by which stronger animals
好的，自然选择又是一个过程，它是更强壮的动物
survive over time and weaker animals don't.
随着时间的推移存活下来，而较弱的动物无法存活的过程。
So if there's a weak species, it can't really survive because it keeps dying and dying,
所以如果有一个弱小的物种，它很难真正存活，因为它不断死亡，
and then finally there's no more.
最后就灭绝了。
And so this is called natural selection because no one's actually choosing what animals will
这被称为自然选择，因为实际上没有人在选择哪些动物会
survive, but it's kind of a natural process.
存活，而是一个自然的过程。
Charles Right, Mother Nature is choosing it.
Charles 对，是大自然母亲在选择。
Katrina Right.
Katrina 对。
Charles Very good.
Charles 很好。
So natural selection, this is one of the things that Darwin is most famous for.
所以自然选择，这是达尔文最著名的一点。
And well, as Katrina mentioned, Darwin wrote the book Origin of the Species.
嗯，正如Katrina提到的，达尔文写了《物种起源》这本书。
Katrina Right, so origin means beginning.
Katrina 对，所以“起源”意思是开始。
So the origin of mankind, right?
比如人类的起源，对吧？
So there are many different kinds of animals.
所以有很多不同种类的动物。
You could even say there are many different kinds of like mammals, but there are many
你甚至可以说有很多不同种类的哺乳动物，但其中又有许多
different species within that.
不同的物种。
So human beings, black bears, koalas, chimpanzees, these are all species.
所以人类、黑熊、考拉、黑猩猩，这些都是物种。
And so a species is a classification.
而物种就是一种分类。
So the origin of the species is kind of a way of telling the story of how all these
所以《物种起源》就像是讲述所有这些事物
things came about.
是如何产生的故事。
Charles All right, the origin of the species.
查尔斯：好的，《物种起源》。
And the last one, this word is kind of strange.
最后一个词有点奇怪。
He talked about the conundrum of the chicken and the egg.
他谈到了鸡和蛋的难题。
Katrina Okay, conundrum.
卡特里娜：好的，难题。
I love this word.
我喜欢这个词。
It's very funny sounding.
听起来很有趣。
Conundrum.
难题。
It means like a problem or a riddle or something that's hard to understand.
它指的是一个问题、谜语或难以理解的事情。
Charles All right.
查尔斯：好的。
So in this case, it's the conundrum of the chicken and the egg, right, which came first.
所以在这个例子里，就是鸡和蛋的难题，对吧，哪个先出现。
How else can you use conundrum?
还能怎么用“难题”这个词？
Katrina You could say that maybe there's a situation
卡特里娜：你可以说也许有一种情况
that's very strange and hard to understand.
非常奇怪且难以理解。
This is quite a conundrum.
这真是个难题。
Charles This is quite a conundrum we have.
查尔斯：我们遇到的这个真是个难题。
It sounds very fancy, very well educated.
听起来很高级，很有教养。
Katrina It does.
卡特里娜：确实。
Charles All right.
查尔斯：好的。
So interesting words on language takeaway.
语言小课堂里这些词真有趣。
Why don't we move on now to four phrases on Fluency Builder.
我们不如现在进入流利度训练的四条短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
All right, on Fluency Builder today, we have four phrases as we said.
好的，今天的流利度训练，我们说了有四条短语。
So what's the first one?
那么第一条是什么？
Katrina The first one is great.
卡特里娜：第一条很棒。
It's very visual.
它很形象。
You say, I'm up to my neck in work.
你说，我工作忙得不可开交。
I'm up to my neck in papers to write.
我写论文忙得不可开交。
All right, so this means I have so much stuff to do that you could pile it up and it would
好的，这意味着我有太多事情要做，以至于可以堆起来
come up to my neck.
堆到我的脖子。
Charles So I have as many papers that are almost as
查尔斯：所以我有那么多论文，几乎和我
tall as I am.
一样高。
Katrina Exactly.
卡特里娜：没错。
And so I could say I'm up to my neck in work.
所以我可以说我工作忙得不可开交。
I have no more time to do anything.
我没有时间做任何其他事了。
Charles Sometimes people also say I'm up to here
Charles 有时候人们也会说“我受够了”
and then they'll like, they'll point at their forehead or somewhere around their head.
然后他们会指着自己的额头或头部附近。
I'm up to here with your nonsense.
我受够了你的胡言乱语。
Katrina Exactly.
Katrina 没错。
So this is a way of saying that I'm really busy.
这是一种表达“我真的很忙”的方式。
Charles Really busy.
Charles 真的很忙。
I'm really tired of it.
我真的厌倦了。
All right.
好的。
And our next phrase is one that most mothers use.
我们的下一个短语是大多数妈妈会用的。
I'm sick and tired.
我烦透了。
Katrina I'm sick and tired of all of your whining.
Katrina 我烦透了你的抱怨。
Go do the dishes and don't complain.
去洗碗，别抱怨了。
Charles Right.
Charles 对。
So it's always, it always goes together.
所以它总是连在一起用。
You are sick and tired.
你烦透了。
Katrina Right.
Katrina 对。
And sick comes first.
而且“烦”在前面。
So I'm sick and tired of this.
所以我烦透了这件事。
I'm sick and tired of your bad attitude.
我烦透了你的坏态度。
Charles Okay.
Charles 好的。
So and that means that you are...
所以这意味着你……
Katrina I'm just tired of it.
Katrina 我就是厌倦了。
I don't want you to have a bad attitude anymore.
我不想你再有坏态度了。
I'm just, yeah.
我就是，嗯。
Charles I'm really annoyed by it.
Charles 我对此很恼火。
I'm annoyed.
我很恼火。
Okay.
好的。
Sick and tired.
烦透了。
And then we saw a phrase that was a little bit separated.
然后我们看到一个稍微分开的短语。
He said the sentence went like this.
他说句子是这样的。
His work turned thousands of years of ideas about creation on their head.
他的工作颠覆了数千年来关于创造的观点。
So to turn something on its head.
所以“彻底颠覆某事物”。
Katrina Like you said, Marco, it's split into two
Katrina 就像你说的，Marco，它分成两
parts.
部分。
So he turned the field of computer science on its head.
所以他彻底颠覆了计算机科学领域。
So to turn on its head means to completely reverse something, to turn it around.
所以“彻底颠覆”意思是完全反转某事物，把它翻过来。
You think 180 degrees.
你想成180度。
And so if biology used to be one way, then Darwin made it completely different.
所以如果生物学以前是一种方式，那么达尔文让它完全改变了。
Charles So we can say that Isaac Newton completely
Charles 所以我们可以说艾萨克·牛顿彻底
turned physics on its head with his theory or his findings on gravity.
用他的引力理论或发现颠覆了物理学。
Katrina And then years and years later, we had Albert
卡特里娜 然后过了很多很多年，我们有了阿尔伯特。
Einstein who turned those theories or who turned that theory on its head with his own
爱因斯坦，他用自己的理论彻底颠覆了那些理论。
ideas about physics.
关于物理学的想法。
Charles Very good.
查尔斯 非常好。
So to turn something on its head, to completely change the course of or prove something to
所以，要让某件事彻底颠覆，完全改变方向，或者证明某事是错的。
be maybe wrong.
可能是错的。
And the last phrase that we have is the person argued that Darwin's theories were full of
我们最后一个短语是，那个人声称达尔文的理论充满了
holes.
洞。
Katrina Okay.
卡特里娜 好的。
So to say a theory is full of holes is a little bit
所以说一个理论漏洞百出，有点……
different than saying that his pants are full of holes.
这和说他的裤子上全是洞不一样。
Because when you say something is full of holes, maybe they actually have holes.
因为当你说某物“漏洞百出”时，可能它真的有很多洞。
But a theory is it's an idea.
但理论就是一种想法。
So it can't have holes.
所以它不能有洞。
What you're saying is that it's not completely sound.
你的意思是说，它并不完全可靠。
It's not without some problems.
也不是没有问题。
And so maybe you're saying that, well, the cookies are gone out of the kitchen, Marco.
所以也许你会说，好吧，厨房里的饼干没了，Marco。
And I saw you in the kitchen.
我在厨房里看到你了。
So clearly you ate the cookies.
所以你显然吃了饼干。
Charles Right.
查尔斯说得对。
So I can say that's full of holes because it was me and it was three other people who
所以我可以这么说，那全是漏洞，因为当时是我和其他三个人一起。
were in the kitchen.
我们在厨房里。
So you can't blame me.
所以你不能怪我。
Katrina Ah, it could have been the other two people.
卡特里娜 啊，可能是另外两个人。
Charles Right.
查尔斯说得对。
So if something is full of holes, it's that it has maybe mistakes or it's still missing
所以如果某件事“漏洞百出”，那意味着它可能有很多错误，或者还有缺失。
complete evidence to prove it right.
完整的证据来证明它是正确的。
Katrina Or it has bad logic.
Katrina 或者它的逻辑有问题。
Charles Bad logic.
查尔斯，逻辑不通。
All right.
好的。
Interesting.
有意思。
So we've taken a look at a lot of words and different phrases here.
所以我们在这里看了很多单词和不同的短语。
Let's listen to this argument one last time.
让我们最后再听一遍这场争论。
Man, it's been forever.
老兄，真是好久不见了。
What have you been up to lately?
你最近在忙什么？
I've been busy preparing for my exams, not to mention all the term papers I've had to
我一直在忙着准备考试，更别提还得写那么多学期论文了。
write.
写。
Same here.
我也是。
I'm up to my neck in work, but at least we've got summer holidays after finals.
我忙得不可开交，但至少期末考试后还有暑假。
Where are you headed now?
你现在要去哪儿？
I'm going to my anthro class.
我要去上人类学课了。
We've been focusing on Darwin all term since it's the 200th anniversary of his birth or
这学期我们一直在讲达尔文，因为今年是他诞辰200周年，还是
whatever.
什么的。
I'm sick and tired of Darwin, Darwin, Darwin.
我烦透了达尔文，达尔文，达尔文。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
How can you not like Darwin?
你怎么能不喜欢达尔文呢？
His work turned thousands of years of ideas about creation on their head.
他的工作颠覆了数千年来关于创世的观念。
His theory of evolution revolutionized the fields of biology and anthropology.
他的进化论彻底改变了生物学和人类学领域。
I don't like him.
我就是不喜欢他。
His theory of human evolution and natural selection is full of holes.
他的人类进化和自然选择理论漏洞百出。
It's not as solid as you make it out to be.
它不像你说的那么站得住脚。
Say that again and you'll make enemies with half of the academy, not to mention your professors.
你再说一遍，就会得罪学院里一半的人，更别说你的教授了。
Furthermore, the explanation proposed by Darwin about the origin of the species and the process
此外，达尔文提出的关于物种起源和自然选择过程
of natural selection constitutes a grand step towards a coherent understanding of the world
的解释，是朝着连贯理解世界
and its very beginnings.
及其起源迈出的重要一步。
I'm not minimizing his huge contributions to science.
我不是在贬低他对科学的巨大贡献。
It's just that his theory reminds me of the conundrum of the chicken and the egg.
只是他的理论让我想起了鸡和蛋的难题。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Which came first, the chicken or the egg?
先有鸡还是先有蛋？
This is a classic logical problem and I think it applies to Darwin's theory.
这是一个经典的逻辑问题，我认为它适用于达尔文的理论。
How did the very first living organism come to be?
第一个生物是怎么出现的？
Interesting.
有意思。
I think that question is better suited for my philosophy class.
我觉得这个问题更适合我的哲学课。
In the meantime, how about we settle this with a duel?
同时，我们不如用决斗来解决这个问题？
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
It's interesting, Darwin's theories and his explanations for the origin of species and
达尔文的理论和他对物种起源以及我们所知的
life as we know it.
生命的解释很有意思。
But there is the opposite to this, right?
但还有与之相反的观点，对吧？
There is a certain thing called creationism.
有一种叫神创论的东西。
There is and this is a big source of controversy, especially in the United States because in
确实有，而且这是一个很大的争议点，尤其是在美国，因为
some places people want to teach creationism as well as evolution in schools.
有些地方人们想在学校里同时教授神创论和进化论。
So this is the big question.
所以这是个重大问题。
Are they still equal as theories or is one theory more proven than the other?
它们作为理论是否仍然平等，还是其中一个理论比另一个更有证据支持？
Right.
对。
And it is kind of hard to determine which one is better because one is based on faith,
而且很难判断哪个更好，因为一个基于信仰，
the other one is based more on scientific evidence, right?
另一个更基于科学证据，对吧？
So they're not really even on the same scale as we learned before.
所以它们甚至不像我们之前学的那样在同一层面上。
That's kind of like apples and oranges, right?
这有点像苹果和橘子，对吧？
It is and there are some people who would say that we have lots of ways of quote unquote
是的，有些人会说我们有很多方法可以“所谓地”
proving what happened in the past but as long as we weren't there, we never really do know.
证明过去发生了什么，但只要我们没有亲身经历，就永远无法真正知道。
And there's always changes in science so how can we be sure that what we know now isn't
科学总是在变化，我们怎么能确定我们现在知道的
false, isn't misunderstanding.
不是错误的、不是误解呢？
I think for now, this is the best explanation but that doesn't mean that it's the correct
我认为目前这是最好的解释，但这并不意味着它是
one.
正确的。
Maybe in a hundred years from now, we'll have another explanation that's much better or
也许一百年后，我们会有另一个更好的解释，
maybe complimentary to this one.
或者是对这个解释的补充。
So we want to know what you guys think, come to our website englishpod.com.
所以我们想知道你们的想法，来我们的网站 englishpod.com。
We really want to hear your opinions.
我们真的很想听听你们的意见。
What do you think about this topic?
你们对这个话题怎么看？
It is a little bit controversial so we really look forward to your comments and any other
这有点争议，所以我们非常期待你们的评论以及
questions you may have.
你们可能有的任何其他问题。
Yep.
是的。
And just a reference, creationism is the idea that God created the world or a superior being
顺便提一下，神创论是指上帝创造了世界，或者一个至高无上的存在
created the world and that everything came from that.
创造了世界，万物都源于此。
And so let us know what you think.
所以请告诉我们你们的想法。
I am very curious too and that's about it for today.
我也很好奇，今天就到这里。
Alright.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
You're taking off for a walk.
你要出去散步了。